Guide to the Julie Gilbert Papers ca. 1940-1998 MSS 38 MSS 038
© 2009 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Printed and written research materials
  - Reproductions of early photos of Paulette G., undated (Box 7, Folder 335)
  - Photo duplications, undated (Box 7, Folder 336)
  - Photo duplications, undated (Box 7, Folder 337)
  - Photo duplications, undated (Box 7, Folder 338)
  - Individual interview with Alpert, Warren, undated (Box 8, Folder 339)
  - Letter of understanding with Monika Anderson, Apr 12, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 340)
  - Individual interview with Albu, Ruth, undated (Box 8, Folder 341)
  - Individual interview with Bellosta, Paula, undated (Box 8, Folder 342)
  - Dietrich- Steve Bach article, undated (Box 8, Folder 343)
  - Individual interview with Bach, Steven, undated (Box 8, Folder 344)
  - Blackglama, undated (Box 8, Folder 345)
  - Individual interview with Bach, Steven- Dietrich book, undated (Box 8, Folder 346)
  - Individual interview with Bellosta, Antoinetta, undated (Box 8, Folder 347)
  - Dietrich, Marlene obituaries, undated (Box 8, Folder 348)
  - Individual interview with Dunham, Ella, undated (Box 8, Folder 349)
  - Blue Angel- The Life of Marlene Dietrich excerpt re: Remarque, undated (Box 8, Folder 350)
  - Freedom of Information Act, undated (Box 8, Folder 351)
  - Individual interview with Fantoni, undated (Box 8, Folder 352)
  - Frazier, James Re: Paulette, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 353)
  - Individual interview with Fairbanks, Douglas, undated (Box 8, Folder 354)
  - Filmographies of EMR and PG, undated (Box 8, Folder 355)
  - Individual interview with Gerard, Rolf, undated (Box 8, Folder 356)
  - Individual interview with Goldsmith, Henry, undated (Box 8, Folder 357)
  - Individual interview with Granato, Lois, undated (Box 8, Folder 358)
  - Individual interview with Gavin, John and notes from various periods, undated (Box 8, Folder 359)
  - Individual interview with Habe, Licci, undated (Box 8, Folder 360)
  - Individual interview with Hau, Michael, undated (Box 8, Folder 361)
  - Individual interview with Horlitz, Margaret- Felix Guggenheim's secretary, undated (Box 8, Folder 362)
  - Individual interview with Kay, Richard, undated (Box 8, Folder 363)
  - Kirkus bio. Review (bad), 1995 (Box 8, Folder 364)
  - Photograph of The Lancia (puma), undated (Box 8, Folder 365)
  - Individual interview with Lantz, Robert, undated (Box 8, Folder 366)
  - Letters from Robert Lantz to EMR, July 3 and Sept. 8, undated (Box 8, Folder 367)
  - Anita Loos, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 368)
  - Individual interview with McCrary, Jinx Falkenburg, undated (Box 8, Folder 369)
  - Individual interview with McKay, Gardner, undated (Box 8, Folder 370)
  - Individual interview with Mankiewitz, Joseph, undated (Box 8, Folder 371)
  - Individual interview with Meredith, Burgess, undated (Box 8, Folder 372)
  - Individual interview with Murray, Helen, undated (Box 8, Folder 373)
  - Individual interview with Morgenroth, Ruth Albu, undated (Box 8, Folder 374)
  - Individual interview with Marton, Ruth, undated (Box 8, Folder 375)
  - Individual interview with Nimoy, Leonard, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 376)
  - Hotel Nikolai- Osnabrück today, undated (Box 8, Folder 377)
  - Osnabrück 1992- archive staff (Box 8, Folder 378)
  - Osnabrück University, undated (Box 8, Folder 379)
  - Paulette pictures, undated (Box 8, Folder 380)
  - Individual interview with Rainer, Luise, undated (Box 8, Folder 381)
  - Reiss, Curtis article in German translated by H. Goldsmith, undated (Box 8, Folder 382)
  - Remarque, Jutta Zambona, undated (Box 8, Folder 383)
  - Individual interview with Rigioria, Luciana, undated (Box 8, Folder 384)
  - Individual interview with Riva, Peter Re: Dietrich, undated (Box 8, Folder 385)
  - Individual interview with Roc, Patricia, undated (Box 8, Folder 386)
  - Royalties 1986-1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 387)
  - Second Chorus picture for advertising campaign, undated (Box 8, Folder 388)
  - Sotheby's auction, undated (Box 8, Folder 389)
  - Individual interview with Selznick, Daniel, undated (Box 8, Folder 390)
  - Individual interview with Schneider, Thomas, undated (Box 8, Folder 391)
  - Individual interview with Smithers, undated (Box 8, Folder 392)
  - Individual interview with Stone, Peter, undated (Box 8, Folder 393)
  - Villa Monte Tabor, undated (Box 8, Folder 394)
  - Biography book parties, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 395)
  - Early attempt at source notes for biography, undated (Box 8, Folder 396)
  - Individual interview with Wolf, Victoria, undated (Box 8, Folder 397)
  - Individual interview with Wiese, Barbara, undated (Box 8, Folder 398)
  - Individual interview with Wallis, Celestine, undated (Box 8, Folder 399)
  - Will of Paulette Goddard Remarque, undated (Box 8, Folder 400)
  - Filmography of EMR, miscellaneous information and Hollywood reporter's allegation re: Frida Kahlo, undated (Box 8, Folder 401)
  - Individual interview with Zernik, Lotte, undated (Box 8, Folder 402)
  - The Writer's Guide to Self-Promotion and Publicity By Elane Feldman, undated (Box 8, Folder 403)
  - Krieg und Literature/ War and Literature v.1 n.1 4/1989 (Box 8, Folder 404)
  - Erich Maria Remarque 1898-1970 Rasch Velag Bramsche, undated (Box 8, Folder 405)
  - Jahrbuch/Yearbook Erich Maria Remarque II/1992 (Box 8, Folder 406)
  - Krieg und Literature/ War and Literature v.1 n.2 1989 (Box 8, Folder 407)
  - Understanding Erich Maria Remarque Hans Wagener, undated (Box 8, Folder 408)
  - Erich Maria Remarque: A literary and film biography, undated (Box 8, Folder 409)
  - Erich Maria Remarque: Der Feind, undated (Box 8, Folder 410)
  - Jahrbuch/Yearbook Erich Maria Remarque, undated (Box 8, Folder 411)
  - Erich Maria Remarque Im Westen Nichts Neues, undated (Box 8, Folder 412)
  - Erich Maria Remarque: a thematic analysis of his novels Peter Lang, undated (Box 9, Folder 413)
  - Paulette: The Adventurous Life of Paulette Goddard by Joe Morella and Edward Epstein, undated (Box 9, Folder 414)
  - Marlene Dietrich by Maria Riva, undated (Box 9, Folder 415)
  - Charles Chaplin: My Autobiography, undated (Box 9, Folder 416)
  - Memo from David O. Selznick ed. Rudy Behlmer, undated (Box 9, Folder 417)
  - Showman: The life of David O. Selznick by David Thomson, undated (Box 9, Folder 418)
  - Fate Keeps on Happening by Anita Loos, undated (Box 9, Folder 419)
  - Sotheby's Magnificent Jewelry, April 1990 (Box 9, Folder 420)
  - Sotheby's Magnificent Jewelry, October 1990 (Box 9, Folder 421)
  - German language publications: Erich Maria Remarque by Rasch Verlag Bramsche; Erich Maria Remarque Friedenspreis der Stadt Osnabrück; Mitteilungen der Erich Maria Remarque Gesellechaft Osnabrück E.V., undated (Box 9, Folder 422)
- Series II: Media
  - Brand: Maxell XLII Contents: Jinx Falkenberg McCrary, undated (Box 10, Object cassette_1)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Audiocassette
  - Brand: Maxell XLII Contents: Jinx Falkenberg McCrary, undated (Box 10, Object cassette_2)
  - Brand: Maxell XLII Contents: Complete "Brown" book, "White" book, undated (Box 10, Object cassette_3)
  - Brand: Maxell XLII Contents: White book conclusion, undated (Box 10, Object cassette_4)
  - Brand: Supertape Extended Range Contents: Bob Collecello on Paulette, undated (Box 10, Object cassette_5)
  - Brand: Memorex dBS Contents: Henry Goldsmith's translation of Remarque's early years, undated (Box 10, Object cassette_6)
  - Brand: Memorex Contents: Henry Goldsmith's translation of early Remarque material, undated (Box 10, Object cassette_7)
  - Brand: Maxell Contents: Henry Goldsmith's translation of Remarque's early life and career, undated (Box 10, Object cassette_8)
  - Brand: Maxell UDII Contents: Henry Goldsmith translating transcript of Elfriede Remarque's trial, undated (Box 10, Object cassette_9)
  - Brand: Panasonic MC-60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
    Microcassette
  - Brand: TDK MC-60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Olympus XB60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Dr. Bissig (Paulette's Doctor during the last years) Julie Gilbert on Luciana Riguron (local boutique owner), undated (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Panasonic MC60 Contents: Ruth Albu- third interview, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Sony MC60 Contents: Dick Kay, 1991 (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Panasonic RT-60MC Contents: #1 B. Wiese, Paulette's physical therapist, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Panasonic RT-60MC Contents: #2 B. Wiese, Paulette's physical therapist, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Panasonic MC 60 Contents: Bob Uhlman on Paulette, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_1)
  - Brand: Certron Contents: Julie on Paulette, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Certron Contents: Julie on Paulette, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: TDK MC60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Panasonic RT-60MC Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: TDK MC60 Contents: Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: TDK MC60 Contents: Bellosta, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Sony MC60 Contents: Peter Stone re: EMR highspeed P.S. is a well known writer, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Olympus XB60 Contents: D. Selznick (David O. Selznick's son) about Paulette, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_2)
  - Brand: Certron Contents: Michael Hall Nove. 1991 Friend of P. Goddard's (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK Contents: Lois Granato, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK Contents: Patricia Roc, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK Contents: Celestine Wallis, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Panasonic RT-60MC Contents: Lotte Zernik (knew EMR), undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus XB Contents: Douglas Fairbanks, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: H.G. my dad, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Panasonic Contents: Dick Kay, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK MC-60 Contents: Sir and Lady Smithers, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: Robby Lantz, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: Helen Murray, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Panasonic Contents: Paul Kohner's Secretary Paul Kohner was EMR's Hollywood agent, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: #2 Thomas Schneider, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: #3 Thomas Schneider, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: #4 Thomas Schneider, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: Olympus Contents: Paola Belosta, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: TDK Contents: Lois Granto, undated (Box 10, Folder micro_3)
  - Brand: 3M Contents: Opposite Attraction, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_1)
    Floppy disk
  - Brand: Bonus by Verbatim Contents: Remarque Wordperfect 5.1 Opposite Attraction, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_2)
  - Brand: Verbatim Contents: Remarque 2 Wordperfect 5.1 Opposite Attraction, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_3)
  - Brand: 3M Contents: Bellosta, Fairbanks, Kay, Lantz, Murray, Selznick, Zernik 1 and 2, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_4)
  - Brand: Unlabeled Contents: Kay 2.51 Richard Kay, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_5)
  - Bonus by Verbatim Wiese 1 and 2.51 Fanto 1.51 Fanto 2 and 3.51 Ger 1 and 2.51 Gold .51, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_6)
  - Brand: 3M Contents: Dunham .51 Meredith .51 Hall .51 Rigbis .51 Horlitz .51 Roc .51 Mart 234.51 Smithers .51 Marton 1.51 Wallis .51, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_7)
  - Brand: Bonus by Verbatim Contents: Habe 1.51 Habe 2.51 Rainer .51 Stone .51 Wolf .51, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_8)
  - Brand: TDK MF-2HD Contents: Remarque Word Perfect 5.1 Dos IBM, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_9)
  - Brand: TDK MF-2HD Contents: Remarque 4.6, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_10)
  - Brand: Global Contents: Remarque Word Perfect 5.1 Part 1, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_11)
  - Brand: Global Contents: Remarque Word Perfect 5.1 Part 2, undated (Box 10, Object Disk_12)